Guide to the Cummings Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Cummings family papers
1794-1886
MS 860
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The principal figures are Charles Cummings, a minister in Sullivan, New Hampshire and his daughter Anna Gove Cummings Boyden. Included are notebooks, account books, and diaries kept by Charles Cummings and schoolbooks of his daughter before her marriage in 1838. Also in the papers are family correspondence and legal and financial papers.
Cummings family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased in 1945.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence and other papers relating to descendants of Joseph Cummings (1745-1788) make up the Cummings Family Papers. Aside from a small amount of correspondence and a variety of deeds and other legal and financial papers relating to lands in New Hampshire, the Papers contain several sermons by Charles Cummings, his diaries, notebook, account book, and journal, as well as essays and a French exercise book of his daughter, Anna Gove (Cummings) Boyden.
These papers were purchased by Yale University in 1945.
Biographical / Historical
Joseph Cummings was born in 1745 and died on September 24, 1788. He grauated from Harvard College in 1768. He married Anna Grove on December 5, 1776. They had six children.
Reverand Charles Cummings was born in 1777 and dies in December 27, 1849. He was a Baptist preacher. He married Polly Hemenway on October 9, 1798. They had seven children.
Cyrus Cummings was born in 1782 and died on April 26, 1827. He married Susan Wildes on May 25, 1809. They had five children. He managed the Topsfield Tavern in Topsfield, Massachusettes.
Source: The Cummings Memorial by George Mooar.
Families; Women -- Education; New England; New Hampshire -- Religion; Sullivan (N.H.); Account books; Diaries; Sermons; Clergy; Boyden, Anna Gove Cummings, b. 1820; Cummings, Charles, 1777-1849; Cummings family
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1802-1886, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Legal and financial papers, 1806-1848 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Charles Cummings (1777-1849)
    - Notebook of arithmetic, 1794-1798 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Diaries, 1806, 1809, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Account book, 1814-1839 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Journal, 1838-1840 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Three sermons, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anna Gove (Cummings) Boyden, 1820-
    - Essays, Circa 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 11)
    - French exercise book [of A. G. Boyden?], Circa 1836 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified autobiographical fragment, 1828 December (Box 1, Folder 13)